## Tairen Piao

Email: tairenpiao@gmail.com > Website: piaotairen.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tairenpiao/

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Research Engineer at Nota Inc., specializing in advanced AI model compression (e.g., quantization) and hardware-aware model optimization methods. Previously, I was a Machine Learning Engineer at Xiaomi, working on Large Language Model (LLM) acceleration and building large-scale recommender systems. I received a master's degree at Seoul National University, advised by Prof. U Kang, where I conducted research related to deep learning model compression.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Research Engineer, NetsPresso Core Research, Nota Inc.

Jul. 2023 - Present

Conduct research on Generative AI model quantization, develop key quantization methods for the Nota NetsPresso platform, Train and deploy various computer vision models to diverse chips and edge devices, and handle various deep learning IR such as ONNX and TFLite.

## Machine Learning Engineer, Al Lab, Xiaomi

Oct. 2021 - Jun. 2023

1) Applied advanced quantization methods to accelerate Xiaomi LLM. 2) Processed million-level data using Spark, developed the entire machine learning (ML) pipeline for the recommender system and optimized the baseline model using ML techniques to improve both accuracy and efficiency.

## Research Assistant, Data Mining Lab, SNU

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2021

1) Conducted deep learning model compression research, including pruning, quantization, and decomposition, and attended a Korean national project. 2) Published an SCI-E paper (SensiMix) related to the mixed precision quantization method on BERT.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Seoul National University**

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2021

M.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

GPA: 4.12 / 4.3 Advisor: *Prof. U Kang* 

#### **Harbin Engineering University**

Aug. 2015 - Jun. 2019

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 3.85 / 4.0

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## [2] EdgeFusion: On-Device Text-to-Image Generation

Thibault Castells, Hyoung-Kyu Song, <u>Tairen Piao</u>, Shinkook Choi, Bo-Kyeong Kim, Hanyoung Yim, Changgwun Lee, Jae Gon Kim, Tae-Ho Kim **CVPR** (EDGE Workshop, 2024)

# [1] SensiMix: Sensitivity-Aware 8-bit Index & 1-bit Value Mixed Precision Quantization for BERT Compression

<u>Tairen Piao</u>, Ikhyun Cho, and U Kang **PLOS ONE** (SCI-E Journal, 2022)

#### Nota Al

- 1. **EdgeFusion.** The goal was to apply quantization to the stable diffusion (SD) model, enabling its deployment on the Samsung Exynos NPU while maintaining accuracy.
  - Mixed Precision Quantization (MPQ). In the SD model, layers such as softmax, swish, and LayerNorm are extremely sensitive to W8A8 quantization. To tackle this, We apply Integer W8A16 quantion to softmax and FP16 to swish and LayerNorm layers.
  - Deploy to Samsung Exynos NPU. By utilizing MPQ and hardware model-level tiling, we successfully deployed the model on the Samsung Exynos NPU. Our EdgeFusion model can generate images in 0.7 seconds.
- 2. **ONNX2TFLite Converter Optimization.** The goal was to optimize the ONNX2TFLite tool to support more ONNX models.
  - NCHW to CNHW. The ONNX format uses NCHW (batch, channels, height, width) ordering to represent the model, while TFLite uses CNHW. During conversion, many operators struggled with this format difference. I fixed various corner cases to support more models.
  - Operator Parameter Issue. During operator conversion, operator parameters need to be copied and mapped to the correct positions in TFLite. I updated the algorithm to support more cases.
- 3. **MPQ for TFLite Vision Models.** The goal was to recover the full INT8 quantized TFLite model accuracy using MPQ.
  - Severe accuracy degradation of full INT8 quantized CV models. The INT8 TFLite uses a
    default min-max quantization scheme. Models like YOLOv5 have severe quantization accuracy loss
    due to many concatenation layers in the detection head of the model.
  - Mixed Precision Quantization. Applied the FP32 precision to the detection head and full INT8 to the remaining part of the model to improve accuracy. For YOLOv5n, the mAP50 of the quantized model is incressed from 0.0 to 0.436.

#### Xiaomi

- 1. Mall Products Recommendation. The goal was to discover the high-potential customers who are interested in purchasing products at the Xiaomi online Mall and offering coupons to some of the top-scoring users to increase Gross Merchandise Volume (GMV). My role involves building the entire MLOps flow, optimizing the model, and measuring the performances of different models by doing AB tests. The highlights are as follows:
  - Million-Level Data Feature Engineering. Using Spark to process the raw features of million-level users and items and doing feature engineering including feature cleaning, pre-processing, and selection.
  - AutoML (NAS and HPO). I designed a DARTs-based NAS method to search for a better recommendation model (search space: generally used Click-Through Rate prediction modules) and applied Random Search-based HPO to optimize the hyper-parameters, which gains 1M dollars income improvement.
- 2. **AI Advertising.** The goal was to improve the Ads' effective Cost Per Mile (eCPM) and model efficiency of the Xiaomi Ad system to improve the customer experience and gain business growth. I mainly focused on optimizing the baseline features and models in the system. The highlights are as follows:
  - Layer-wise Knowledge Distillation (KD). To overcome the Query Per Second (QPS) bottlenecks of servers caused by the large model size, I applied layer-wise KD to shrink the model size, which reduces half of the model inference time and even achieves 5% higher eCPM.

 Model Optimization. I designed a multi-task model combined with a context-aware embedding enhancing method to improve the performance. Besides, I applied different CTR calibration methods to different Ad slots to improve the final eCPM. Overall, the optimized model gains 10% eCPM improvement.

## Data Mining Lab @ SNU

- 1. SensiMix (BERT 1&8-bit Quantizaion). The goal was to compress the pre-trained BERT model to a lightweight one while maintaining its accuracy. We propose SENSIMIX that effectively applies 8-bit and 1-bit mixed precision quantization to the sensitive and insensitive parts of BERT, maximizing the compression rate while minimizing the accuracy drop. We also propose three novel 1-bit training methods to minimize the accuracy drop and apply XNOR-Count GEMM to 1-bit quantization parts of the model to accelerate the inference speed on Turing NVIDIA GPUs. Experiments show that SENSIMIX reduced the original BERT model size by a factor of 8× and shrinking the inference time by around 80% without a noticeable accuracy drop.
  - SensiMix accepted by PLOS One 2022. More specific methodology and experimental results can be found in the paper.
  - Deploy to Android Devices. To make the compressed model inference on real edge devices, I deployed the SemsiMix model to Android phones based on the PyTorch Mobile framework. The 1-bit XNOR GEMM kernel is also ported to the Android platform. The kernel implementation is open-sourced, which can be found in <a href="https://github.com/tairenpiao/XNOR-popcount-GEMM-PyTorch-CPU-CUDA">https://github.com/tairenpiao/XNOR-popcount-GEMM-PyTorch-CPU-CUDA</a>
- 2. **BERT Model Compression.** I was a research assistant at SNU Data Mining Lab focused on BERT model compression. Besides quantization, I also applied various pruning, KD, and factorization methods on the BERT model, and also achieved good accuracy and inference speed.

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### **Teaching Asssistant**

| • | SK-Univ, SK                                     | . Aug 2020  |
|---|---|-------------|
| • | Data Structures (M1522.000900), SNU             | . Fall 2020 |
| • | Introduction to Data Mining (M1522.001400), SNU | Spring 2020 |

## **PATENTS**

- <u>Tairen Piao</u>, "A Cross-Task Knowledge Distillation Model for Multi-Task CTR Prediction, CN-Registration (2023)
- 2. <u>Tairen Piao</u>, "Layer-Wise Knowledge Distillation Method for Compressing CTR Prediction Models.", CN-Registration (2022)
- 3. <u>Tairen Piao</u>, "Auto Feature Selection Method for CTR Prediction Models based on Power Law Data Distribution.", CN-Registration (2022)
- 4. <u>Tairen Piao</u>, Ikhyun Cho, and U Kang, "Quantization Method For Transformer Encoder Layer based on the Sensitivity of the Parameter and Apparatus Thereof", KR-Registration No. 10-2020-0183411 (2020)

## **SKILLS**

Programming Language: C, C++, Python, CUDA, Java, Shell, SQL

Frameworks and Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, TFLite, ONNX, TensorRT, MLPack

Spark, Pandas, Optuna, Matplotlib, Git, Docker

Language: Korean (Advanced), English (Advanced), Mandarin (Native)